a couple times about edge and off ball
linebacker. Is there a sense that there
might be more bang for the buck at 19
for one of those positions more than the
other?
>> Maybe. Um, you know, I think there'll
definitely there'll be a linebacker
there we like. There'll be a edge that
we probably like there too. So, we just
really got to weigh that with free
agency and just kind of see like how it
goes in free agency. And then, you know,
I think you always adjust your plan
based off, you know, what you did in
free agency. But that's not to say that
we wouldn't double dip at a certain
position, whether edge or linebacker or
both.
>> Knowing that you invested though in
outside linebacker this past year, is
that put middle linebacker at all over
that as far as priorities right now?
>> No, I don't think so. Um, I think uh,
again it's just about getting the best
players and you know if we feel like the
best player is another edge rusher, I
don't think you can ever have too many
edge guys. So that's kind of the stance
we're taking right now.
>> Dan, you've been so measured in the last
two years in terms of this rebuild. As
you get closer to where you want to be,
how do you stay patient and sort of
maintain that approach?
>> Yeah, I mean, we're aligned in the
building. We have a plan. We're going to
stick to that plan. um we're going to
stay disciplined. Um that doesn't mean
we're not going to be aggressive and
take swings, but you know, we're going
to be smart. We're going to be
calculated in what we do in our
approach. Um yeah, you know, I think
between myself and and Brandt and Coach
Canales, you know, we're always talking
about the roster and ways to get better.
And you know, we we do have to stay
smart and disciplined, but again, that
doesn't mean we're not going to be
aggressive. When you say be aggressive,
are you meaning in free agency or
overall?
>> Yeah, I think, you know, free agency,
you know, draft, you know, like we did
last year, we traded up in the draft
when we felt like we, you know, a player
could help us out. Um, and in free
agency, same thing. I think you've seen
um in my three years that, you know, in
free agency, we're going to get the best
players. We're going to try to get the
best players and and be aggressive when
we see fit. you've been so outspoken
about getting youth at quarterback
behind Bryce. What are your
conversations like with Andy? Where are
you guys at from from the standpoint of
having Andy involved in the plan?
>> Yeah, I think um you know I think with
not just Andy but with all the players I
try to stay, you know, honest and
transparent with, you know, our plans
and no different with Andy. You know,
Andy knows he's going to have to
compete. Um we are going to try to bring
somebody in here. I don't know who that
is. whether through free agency or the
draft or you know again both. You never
know. So um I'm I'm in constant
communication with Andy. We've talked
multiple times and um you know he's
aware of the plan and we'll see what
happens.
>> Depending on who you were to bring in,
could that end Andy's tenure with him?
>> You know, I think it's, you know, really
up to Andy. You know, I think um in
terms of Andy competing, you know,
Andy's not afraid of competition. So,
um, we'll see. We'll see what happens in
free agency. We'll see what happens in
the draft, and then, you know, we'll see
how it plays out.
>> And talking about those linebackers,
what's the number one priority in terms
of what that guy needs to have, needs to
bring?
>> Um, I would say number one thing is, you
know, standing in front of that huddle,
all those those 10 other guys are
looking at you. I think that guy has to
be a really good leader. um somebody
that the guys are going to follow,
somebody that the guys are going to
respect, and then obviously from a
playing standpoint, you have to be
instinctual, you have to be smart, you
have to be tough, you have to be
physical. Um, you know, those are the
type of guys we want to bring in here
and and he's got to fit with our
culture. He's got to be our type of guy.
>> With Cade, he's kind of had like an up
and down kind of tenure with you guys.
He's hitting free agency. there's not
really a lot of center options on the
market. How much do you have to kind of
weigh how much you've invested in the
other four positions as you kind of
evaluate his situation?
>> Yeah, I think you definitely have to
weigh that. Um, you know, in terms of
the price and, you know, I think Cade,
you know, I'm sure his agents meeting
with people and figuring out what his
market's looking like right now. And,
you know, once once he figures that out,
we'll reassess. And, you know, we've
been in constant communication with his
agent. So again, we'll see how it goes
and see how it plays out. But um Kate
Kade is a guy that we would want to
bring back, you know, if it works out
for both sides.
>> And it sounds like and at least with
Rico and Cade who are among your or are
your top two ranks.
>> It sounds like you're you're not really
prioritizing anyone in terms of letting
them test the market first. Is that true
with all of your your free agents?
>> It is. It is. Yeah, we're um again,
we're they've earned the right to go out
there and and find the best deal for
themselves. Um you know, do we want some
of them back? Yes, we do. But, um again,
they've earned the right to go out there
and, you know, find a find a bigger
deal.
>> Seems like, correct me if I'm wrong, you
haven't been asked about Bryce on the
podium for two years.
>> It's a good thing.
>> I mean, I'm going to say, what what does
that say to you, the fact that you're
not being asked about that on? Yeah, I
think it it speaks a lot about Bryce and
and his maturity, the way that he's
matured and the way that he's grown as a
quarterback uh throughout his tenure and
he was definitely put in some tough
situations and you know, we're starting
to surround him with some weapons and uh
we'll continue to add to the offensive
line to protect him and um he's just
getting better and better every year.
I'm proud of him and um yeah, he's just
he's he's doing great and you know, I
think the future's really bright for
him.
>> In your postseason press conference, you
said y'all had like 600 players on your
draft.
>> Yeah.
>> I'm curious, how do you work through
that? Has it grown and then how do you
work through that draft board as as the
progress?
>> Um it's actually shrunk now. So, you
know, we've uh you know, as you go
through the process, you always start
with a bunch of guys and then you kind
of whittle it down to, you know, your
type of guys, whether you take guys off
the board for character reasons or
they're not a culture fit or, you know,
they're not a schematic fit. Um, so
yeah, like we've whittleled our board
down a little bit and it'll keep kind of
shrinking as we get closer to the draft.
And um it's a full process. It's a
yearly process and it's a lot of work,
but it's a lot of fun and and we're
excited about the draft.
>> You said on a radio show uh you didn't
say it to us, but I think you said on a
radio show you wanted to bring in
potentially a yards after catch type
receiver.
>> Is that someone you could take in the
first round and go three years in a row?
>> I mean, I'm not ruling anything out. I
think it's one of those things like I've
told you guys from the beginning, we're
not going to pass up on good players.
And if that best player that's on our
board is is a wide out that has run
after catch, then you know, so be it.
Um, but we're not going to pass up on
good players.
>> And will you talk to Conception this
week? Is he a guy that's that's on your
>> Yeah, I mean, we're we're very aware of
him along with, you know, all the other
receivers. It's a deep receiver class.
There's a lot of talented guys that
we're excited about and we'll see where
it goes.
>> Dan, last year when you signed some
guys, you put a lot of incentives into
their contracts. When you guys had
success, they had success including the
playoffs.
>> Why was that important to you guys? And
is it a strategy you think you now that
you've made the playoffs that you'll
continue?
>> Yeah, I think, you know, Brandt does a
really good job of that. Um, I do think
it's a case byase basis. Um, and you
know, it's always good to put that type
of stuff in there. you know, not that
certain guys need incentives, but you
know, it also doesn't hurt, you know,
that you know, you have a little bone
kind of out there for you if if you you
know, if you have success, if the team
has success. So, yeah, I think it's
something that um Brandt does a good job
with and I'm sure he'll he'll do it if
he sees fit.
>> Speaking of wide out and Xavier had a
pretty rough year, what have your
offseason conversations been like?
>> They've been good. They've been good.
Uh, you know, Xavier, he's hungry. He's
hungry to go out there and and and play
his best and and not to prove anybody
wrong, but um but to prove himself
right. Um I know he's I know he's
motivated. He's going to put the work in
this off seasonason like he always does.
Um I'm excited for him. You know, I
think uh he's he's definitely taking a
beating, you know, from a outside
perspective, but we have full belief in
him and and um I'm excited for him and
his future.
>> All right. you uh
>> you mentioned at the end of season press
conference that
>> you were going to go ahead do the
fifthear option on Bryce
>> um I think we asked you if you were
looking extension at all is that
anywhere in the plans right now
>> Brandt and I you know we're still going
through that along with coach Canales
like we're still talking talking through
strategywise but I really don't have
anything on that right now. Can you talk
to us about obviously the news Brad is
it um calling plays now? Dave said that
y'all had a conversation about that. Can
you take us through the process of
making that change?
>> Yeah. Um, you know, I think, uh, coach,
uh, through the whole evaluation
process, um, I think, you know, coach
wanted to kind of take a step back and,
you know, be a head coach, if you want
to say, to where, you know, he's able to
have his hand in both sides of the ball
and, you know, he feels like Brad's
ready and ready to roll. And I have
complete confidence in in um, you know,
coach's decision and I'm excited for
Brad and I think he's going to do a
great job.
that you guys don't always agree, but
everyone is hurt. And he also admitted,
you know, his ego came into play a
little bit in making this decision. Can
you just talk about the trust that you
guys have in each other to make a big
decision like that?
>> Yeah, we we definitely, you know, we're
not always going to agree on every
little thing and we shouldn't, you know,
and um I think at the end of the day,
like we're always going to collaborate
on everything. We're going to bounce
ideas off each other. Um, but at the end
of the day, we're gonna do what's best
for the Carolina Panthers. Um, and
that's that's our motto and everything
that we do. Um, it's not about me. It's
not about Coach Canals. It's about
what's best for the organization. And,
you know, coach feels like that's the
best thing. And, you know, I fully
support him.
>> Dan, you've known Brad since he was like
in grade school.
>> Yeah.
>> To see him be able to to have this
opportunity
>> and have that perspective Yeah. How cool
is that?
>> It's It's cool. You know, I I've known
Brad for a while now and you know, his
dad I worked with his dad out in Seattle
and uh he's super smart. Um he loves the
game. Um you know, he has a lot of good
ideas, a lot of, you know, things that
I'm excited to kind of see come about.
And um that's not to put pressure on
him, but I'm I'm excited to see what he
can do. And um I know we'll take full
advantage of the opportunity. When you
hired Dave, it was, you know, you had
familiarity with him, but it was also a
big part of him his success with
quarterbacks, his offense.
>> Will he be potentially able to impact
Bryce in a different and or greater way
in this role?
>> Yeah, I think so. um you know when he's
out on the practice field he's usually
you know in his mic talking to the
quarterback and not necessarily like you
know harping on every little detail with
Bryce and the rest of the quarterback
room. So I think it's a good opportunity
for him to kind of take a step back kind
of see the big picture of things and um
again be a head coach. Um, you know, I
know he's excited about it and I know he
has full confidence in Brad and Beville
and, you know, those guys to go and and
attack it.
>> Can you tell us something about Brad
from early days that we don't know now
that
>> I mean I want you to tell us?
>> I don't really know. I mean, I knew him
when he was like younger, but like in
terms of like little things that you
wouldn't know, like it's probably the
same stuff. I don't know. So,
>> yeah.
>> Be's a big piece of this. you have
background with him, too. How pivotal
was was bringing him in this this off
season?
>> I think I think it's huge. Um, you know,
I think when you can add a veteran with
that much experience and, you know, he
has play calling history as well. So,
um, he's been in a lot of different
offenses around the league, he's got to
see a lot. So to have that, you know,
glossery of information that that he has
in his brain about about football, you
know, is going to be invaluable to, you
know, not just not just Brad, but the
rest of the staff and and coach Canales.
>> Canales admitted that there were moments
in looking back at the season where if
he didn't have to focus on getting to
the next play, maybe he could have
affected the game in a different way.
>> In the moment, did you see kind of that
and how that that could have been a
benefit to the team?
>> Yeah, I think so. Um, you know, there
are times last year when, you know,
we're down and, you know, there's really
nobody like there to be like get the
guys up on the sideline and, you know,
and that's coach's superpower. You know,
he's a he's a motivator. You know, he
gets the guys going and um yeah, so I
think yeah, there was times where he
definitely could have been used um
useful in that in that way. you kind of
navigating the sideline and talking to
the defense, talking to the offense, but
you know, when you're the play caller,
you got to be in that play sheet and you
know, you're fully focused on that. So,
it kind of takes you away from
everything else.
>> Just to be clear,
>> just to be clear, you never like came up
and said, "Dave,
>> no." Okay.
>> No, that's that is not me. That's not
like his decisions are are his.
Obviously, we talk about it before he
does it, but
>> Yeah. Like,
>> another that is the Dom leaving. Um he's
obviously a guru in a 34. Yeah.
>> Um and and so is Ever is him leaving at
all to do with maybe you guys want to be
more versatile like or flexible and go
to different defenses?
>> No, I think I think it's about you know
just
uh EJ has a good a good staff and and
guys that he has a lot of confidence in.
So, I think it's going to allow, you
know, some of his staff to just kind of
like, you know, learn and like keep
helping him out and and, you know,
advance them, if you want to say. So,
um, I I don't think it's so much about
that as it is just like giving other
people like opportunities to to advance
and, you know, help him out. It sounded
like you were you were saying that he
will have more of a chance to impact
players during games more so than
working officials. Uh timeouts, game
management, both.
>> Both. Yeah, both. like he'll be able to
do all that,
>> yell at the officials and you know just
>> Was there a moment last year I asked him
this where you were like man that would
have been a good one to challenge or if
he weren't you know
>> um I I'm not like uh you know we'll talk
about things but I'm not one that's
going to be like why didn't you
challenge this or why didn't you
challenge that? So like we just talk
through things after the game like where
we could have been better or you know
what we could have done differently. So
like we're always talking about ways to
get better. So that's just another
example.
>> Understanding that it was Dave's
decision. What have you seen from Brad
that makes you feel confident that this
is he's ready?
>> Yeah, I mean I talk to him all the time
just about you know his off the offense
and like his philosophy and like he's
smart. um he puts the work in. He's a
grinder and he's he gets along with all
the players. Like he knows our players
and he knows their strengths and
weaknesses. So yeah, I have confidence
that him and his team are going to be
able to like put great game plans
together and and
do well.